NYSUT Legislative Department Files. 6174/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; letter to managers advising them that payroll deduction was now available for contributions to VOTE/COPE; list of managers contributing through payroll deduction, and those not participating; VOTE/COPE financial statements; letter from NYSUT general counsel to accounting firm Buchbinder Tunick and Co.
- Vote/Cope Managers' Drive, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; lists of those who contributed and had not yet contributed
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; status of number contributing, noting average contribution; reminder memos; letter to Lubin from AFT political director, noting contribution to VOTE/COPE, with attached copy of check, March 1, 1996
- Vote/Cope Letters, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; reminder memos
- Community School Board Reform Bill Draft (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Text of draft legislation; Assembly version
- Walk Through Memo, Weingarten Memo, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Memo from Randi Weingarten to Ray Skuse summarizing Community School Board Reform legislation; walk-through memorandum with section-by-section summary of amendments
- Legislative Programs, 1976-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Spiral-bound booklets for NYSUT legislative agenda, April 20, 1976, January 24, 1976, March 22, 1978, April 5, 1979
- Legislative Programs, 1980-1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  NYSUT legislative programs
- Legislative Programs, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Preliminary and updated NYSUT legislative programs, including bills applicable to United University Professions
- Legislative Programs, 1973-1977 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Tentative and updated NYSUT legislative programs, including bills applicable to Professional Staff Congress of CUNY, 1977
- Legislative Programs, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Tentative and final NYSUT legislative programs and related memos
- Legislative Program Original, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  NYSUT legislative program
- Legislative Material NYSUT New Local Presidents Conference, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Political Action Committee Guidelines for Political Endorsements for NYSUT; brochure explaining VOTE/COPE; Campaign '84 Instruction Booklet; suggested payroll deduction plan; 1984 Legislative Report and Previous Accomplishments; 1984 Legislative Program; position paper, "NYSUT's Triborough Legislation: Why It Is Necessary," May 1982; NYS School Boards Association press release, "Early Retirement Bill Would Worsen Teacher Shortage," June 15, 1984; text of early retirement legislation; "Invisible Victories: Bills Held by the Legislature Due to Efforts of NYSUT"; NYSUT memoranda of support or opposition
- Legislative Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Booklets, "The Impact of Executive Proposals on State Aid to Public Education 1991-92"; "1991 NYSUT Legislative Program for Pension Equity"; "Delegate Selection Process: Campaign '92"; "1992 Summary of New Legislation Affecting Education"; NYSUT 1991 Legislative Program
- Legislative Programs, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  1991 Annual Report of the New York State Senate Standing Committee on Education; NYSUT booklet, "Delegate Selection Process: Campaign '92"; "Teacher Resource and Computer Training Centers Located in the Districts of Assembly Ways and Means Committee Members and Senate Finance Committee Members"; NYSUT Committee of 100 Pension, Retirement and Labor Issues, May 17- 18, 1993; "AFT and NYSUT Support: FY 93 Chapter 1 Supplemental Appropriations, Chapter 1 Reauthorization Issues, Comprehensive Health Care Reform Package"
- Legislative Programs, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  NYSUT Legislative Program and Support Bills Signed into Law, 1991 and 1992; NYSUT's Major Legislative Program and Support Bills 1993 Final Report; NYSUT Committee of 100 Pension and Retirement Issues, May 18-19, 1992; NYSUT Legislative Program 1992; NYSUT 1993 Legislative Program; Personal Income Tax Reform: A NYSUT Proposal; Executive Budget Recommendations 1993-94: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; 1993 Summary of New Legislation Affecting Education, State Education Department; Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges
- Legislative Reports to Board, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Legislative updates to NYSUT Board of Directors and Executive Committee re governor's state aid proposal re K-12, key bills, presidential election telephone calling update
- Legislative Reports to Board, 1985-1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Executive vice president's reports; notes for Executive Committee meetings re governor's state of the state message, election of Regents, small city school district (Hurd) state aid, tuition tax credits, delegates to Democratic National Convention
- Voter Registration Packet, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Voter registration forms; instructions; booklet; question and answer sheet; roster of county boards of election; description of Federal Election Commission and regulations
- Photographs (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Black and white photos of NYSUT officials with governor Hugh Carey, Senate Majority Leader Ralph Marino, other state elected officials
- FNHP Lobby Days, 2000-2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Materials for Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Lobby Day 2000: Lists of members of Assembly and state Senate, with office numbers; list of members of legislative health and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; debriefing form (reporting on results of individual visits with legislators); NYSUT/FNHP handbook, "What Every Health Care Processional Should Know"; FNHP Policy Statements on the Use of Unlicensed Assistive Personnel, on the Definition of Safe Health Care Staffing Levels, on School Nurse Staffing Levels; NYSUT/FNHP Lobby Day statements supporting Legislation to Allow Registered Nurses to Honor Non-Hospital Do Not Resuscitate Orders, and Legislation to Enact NYS Whistle Blower Protection for Health Care Workers; Memoranda in Support of various bills; cards reminding lobbyists to ask for action on specific legislation; materials for FNHP Lobby Day 2002: text of legislation; materials for 2004 re ending mandatory overtime, other legislative issues
- Teacher Center Lobby Day, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Agendas for Teacher Center Lobby Day; Rogers' Pocket Directory: Your Guide to the NYS Senate, Assembly, Members of Congress, 1998 edition; testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to legislative finance committees re 1998-99 Executive Budget recommendations for education; bullet points re Teacher Centers; related materials; invoices
- Retiree Lobby Days, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Briefing booklet, Tier Equity and Pension Improvement Lobby Day, June 4, 1997; lists of members of Assembly and Senate; briefing book for 1998; related memos
- Political Action Committee, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  Workshop agenda; booklet, "Talking about: NYSUT's Positions on the Issues: A Series of Talking Points on Topics of Concern"; local union information sheet (form)
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1997-2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Agendas; lists of members of Assembly and Senate; lists of members of finance and education committees; testimonies of NYSUT and United University Professions officials to legislative finance committee hearings; letters of invitation to community college local presidents; (missing 1999 and 2001)
- NYSUT Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Booklets, "Campaign '88: November 12-14 Congressional District Liaison Conference," "Education. The State of Excellence: CUNY State Aid 1988-89," "SUNY State Aid 1988-89," "K-12 State Aid 1988-89"; legislative memoranda of support for various bills; flyers/print ads; opposition advertisements and legislative bulletins by NYS School Boards Association; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson
- New Local Presidents' Conference, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Agenda; NYSUT briefing booklets, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity: Long Overdue, 1990," "Major Legislation of Interest: Higher Education and Health Care Professionals, 1989," NYUST 1990 Legislative Program," "NYSUT Focus on K-12 1989," "NYSUT's Committee of 100: SUNY, CUNY, and the Community Colleges, March 5-6, 1990-91" "K-12 State Aid 1990-91"; 1990 VOTE/COPE Instruction Booklet; VOTE/COPE general brochure; NYSUT brochure encouraging registration and voting
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on K-12, UFT (NYC), SUNY, CUNY, and SUNY community colleges; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12 and NYC, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on K-12, UFT (NYC), SUNY, CUNY, SUNY community colleges, and health care; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; flyers, March for Public Education; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Agenda for June Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12 and NYC, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on UFT NYC, SUNY, CUNY, and SUNY community colleges; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; reporting forms for feedback on reactions of individual legislators; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Agenda for March lobby Day; briefing book re K-12, NYC budget priorities, and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; reporting forms for feedback on reactions of individual legislators
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book K-12, NYC budget priorities, and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees
- NYSUT Committee of 100 (C100), 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book re K-12, NYC, higher education, and health care; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book re K-12 and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1998-2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Briefing books for Lobby Day
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Agenda for June Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Agenda for February Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; NYSUT Proposal for State Aid and Education Reform in New York State 1984-85; Tuition Tax Credit and Deduction Fact Sheet; Statement of Albert Shanker, President, United Federation of Teachers, before a Legislative Hearing of the NYS Standing Committee on Education, February 10, 1984; list of members of Committee of 100
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; briefing book, "1985-86 Public Schools State Aid Proposals: NYSUT/ECB and Executive Budget"; NYSUT legislative memoranda of support or opposition; brochure by NYS Educational Conference Board, 1985 State Aid Proposal
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; NYSUT legislative memoranda of support; NYSUT 1986 Legislative Program; NYSUT 1985 Legislative Report; briefing book, "Teacher Salary Aid Proposal"
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate and finance committees; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; print ads/flyers; briefing books on K-12 state aid, SUNY and CUNY; fact sheets on community colleges
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Agenda for February Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate and higher education committees; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; print ads/flyers; briefing book re SUNY and CUNY; related notes
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  Lists of new state legislators, members of Assembly and Senate finance committees; print ads/flyers; briefing books re SUNY, CUNY, and community colleges and K-12 state aid
- NYSUT Committee of 100, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing books, "Higher Education Issues," "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity: Long Overdue 1990"
- NYSUT Endorsements, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  Booklets, NYSUT Endorsements, Endorsement Recommendations (NYS Assembly, U.S. Congress); memos; letter to local presidents
- NYSUT Endorsements, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Agenda for Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; NYSUT Policy on Endorsements; NYSUT booklets, "Congressional Voting Record, 2003-04," "Brief Description of Bills Used for Voting Records, U.S. Congress," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, U.S. Congress," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, NYS Senate," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, NYS Assembly," "NYS Assembly Voting Record," 2003 and 2004; "NYS Assembly Background Information," "NYS Senate Voting Record" 2003 and 2004; "NYS Senate Background Information"; "NYS Assembly 2003 Veto Overrides for Public Education"; overrides by Senate; NYSUT campaign flyers for John Kerry for president
- NYSUT Endorsements, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Booklets re endorsement recommendations for NYSUT Presidents' Conference and Executive Committee/Board of Directors for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills
- NYSUT Endorsements, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- NYSUT Endorsements, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- NYSUT Endorsements, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  Booklets re NYSUT endorsement recommendations for congressional and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills
- NYSUT Endorsements, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  Booklets re background information for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates (voting records, descriptions of bills)
- NYSUT Endorsements, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Booklets re NYSUT endorsement recommendations for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates; phone script for member survey re presidential candidate preference; phone script for calls urging support for congressional, state Senate, and Assembly candidates; "Clinton to Educate All of America" bumper sticker and button, with NYSUT logo; fact sheet comparing Dole and Clinton records; memo from Alan Lubin to regional staff directors re fall election activities; lists of Political Action Committee members who attended and who did not attend endorsement conference